### MOCHAMMAD IBNU ABBAS



in Mochammad Ibnu Abbas | ( ibnume



I am a Geology Engineering graduate with several years of work experiences. However, I have an interest and want to develop in the field of technology. I am a conscientious person who works hard and pays close attention to detail. I am quick to pick up new skills and eager to learn from others.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

Geotechnician

Feb 2022 - Jan 2024

PT.Indonesia Carbon Energy (job site PT.Berau Coal)

Berau, East Kalimantan

- Evaluation of plan vs. actual drilling.
- Core logging full coring method (collecting data of physical characteristics of rocks, weathering level, RQD, GSI, rock defect, roughness), Pumping test, slug test, and piezometer installation.
- Soil logging (SPT method: boundary swamp, physical characteristics, plasticity).
- Incline drain hole (open hole drilling).
- Geotech sampling: (UCS, DS, and UDS).

## **Wellsite Geologist**

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

PT.Indonesia Carbon Energy (job site PT.Berau Coal)

Berau, East Kalimantan

- Survey (stake out) location of drilling plan, and stake in by the SGI department, Moving rig, drill pad and access planning.
- Drilling activities (open hole drilling, part-coring drilling).
- Reporting and evaluation of drilling activities.

# **Wellsite Geologist**

Sept 2021 - Nov 2021

PT.Quantus Consultant Indonesia (job site PT.Nunukan Bara Sentosa Satu (Medco Group)

Sei Manggaris, North Kalimantan

 Survey (stakeout) the location of the drilling plan, Moving rig, drill pad, and access planning.

#### **Mapping Surveyor**

Aug 2020 - Sept 2021

**BAPENDA DKI Jakarta** 

- Mapping the areas of buildings such as houses, office buildings, restaurants, hotels, and entertainment venues in an area based on the land and building taxes
- Coordinating with local governments to verify mapped buildings.
- Produce digitation building maps using supporting software (ArcGIS/QGIS).

# **CERTIFICATES**

<ul> <li>Bahasa</li> <li>English</li> <li>Team Work</li> <li>ArcGIS/QG</li> </ul>	ilS
LANGUAGES SKILLS IT SKILLS  • Bahasa • Communication • Ms.Office	
Al-Haramain Saudi Academy Senior High School	2011 - 2014
Pakuan University Geological Engineering / GPA 3.10	2014 - 2019
EDUCATION	
Pakuan University, Bogor – 2014/2018	2014 - 2018
Students Executive Board (BEM)	
Pakuan University, Bogor – 2015/2018	
Association of Geological Engineering Students	2015 - 2018
ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCES	
Emergency First Aid Training (PPGD)  (PT.Berau Coal)	2022
(PT.Bara Indo Berjaya)	2023
Competency Frontline Operation Management (Pengawas Operasional Pertama	BNSP) <sub>2023</sub>
(Purwadhika)	
Bootcamp Full-Stack Web Developer	2024
TRAINING & COURSES	
Conservation of Minerals and Impact of the Problem Solved (ASSOCIATION OF INDONESIA GEOLOGIST)	2014
(SKK MIGAS)	
General Lecture of Oil and Gas Industry	2017
Case Studies Open Pit Methods and Mining Management Programs (MINERBA)	
E-Certificate Estimation Overview of Minerals Reserves	2020
Bootcamp Full-Stack Web Developer Certificate (PURWADHIKA)	2024
Postesman Full Stock Mich Douglaner Contificate	2024

- English
- Arabic

- Problem Solving
- Time Management
- ArcGIS/QGIS
- Global Mapper
- JavaScript
- React JS
- Node JS